

Justin Carville

Data Scientist

Tokyo, Japan

Contact Info

jccarville@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/jccarville/

https://github.com/justIntlme



Click for Portfolio & Projects

Technical Skills

- Python
- Scikit-Learn
- Machine Learning
- NLP
- Deep Learning
- Computer Vision
 - SQL
 - Google Cloud Platform
 - Streamlit
 - Git/Github

Languages

English : native

Japanese : businessSpanish : conversational

Education

- Le Wagon Tokyo (2023)
 #1 ranked bootcamp worldwide
 9-week intensive data science
 bootcamp
- KICL Kyoto (2017-2019)
 Japanese language school
 Passed JLPT N2
- University of Rhode Island (2010-2013)

Bachelor of Arts in Spanish, Journalism Graduated Magna Cum Laude

Interests

- Link to my music here
- weightlifting
- yoga
- hiking

About Me

"Every day is a new adventure." This philosophy brought me to Japan in 2017, where I have since leveraged my love of languages to make a living. My experience working in marketing and business operations got me excited about coding and data, so I changed gears and am now on a mission to become fluent in this new field.

Professional Experience

• Link Academy (2019-2023)

SNS Marketing Specialist

- SNS video content creation for YouTube, Instagram
- KPI analysis
 - o 70+ videos, 66,000+ views, 220+ subscribers

Operations Support Staff

- Lesson schedule optimization, management
- Troubleshooting and IT support
 - o avg of 60 lessons booked / week

ESL Teacher

- Teach conversation, business, TOEIC, pronunciation lessons
 - 95% student feedback rate
- Freelance Writer, Editor, Translator (2018-2023)

WeLoveOsaka (link to articles)

 translate (J→E) and edit articles about tourism, gourmet, events

AtoZ English

• write, edit test content for EIKEN, TOEIC, TEAP

Grape Japan (link to articles)

- write, translate articles on Japanese culture, lifestyle, trends
- **VIPKID** | ESL Teacher (2017-2019)
 - teach online English lessons for children
 - 1000+ classroom hours
- CCRI | Tutor (2016-2017)
 - teach one-on-one lessons in Biology, Anatomy, Physiology, Math
- NPR | Copy Editor, Contributor (2015-2016)
 - field work, interviews, articles, edits for radio and online